welcome to another darktable tutorial in
欢迎来到中的另一个暗表教程
this video we're going to be taking
我们将要拍摄的这段视频
these raw images that we got from we
这些我们从我们那里得到的原始图像
saturate calm and I'll show you how to
保持冷静 我会教你怎么做
apply a watermark over top of the image
在图像顶部应用水印
you can either apply it directly over
您可以直接将其应用于
top like this we can put it our own
像这样的上衣我们可以把它放在我们自己的
custom on in the bottom corner so I'll
在底角打开定制 这样我就可以
call you I'll show you a couple
给你打电话 我给你看几个
different ways that you can do that
你可以用不同的方式做到这一点
we do that in the darkroom it's actually
我们在暗室里这样做 实际上是
a module so let's apply one to this
一个模块 所以让我们将一个应用到这个
image right here we go to darkroom and
图像就在这里 我们走进暗室
we see I already have it brought in here
我们知道我已经把它送到这里了
but if you don't have yours it's not
但如果你没有你的 那就不是了
here in your favorites by default you
默认情况下 在您的收藏夹中
need to go to more modules in the bottom
需要转到底部的更多模块
right hand corner and then just search
右下角 然后搜索
for watermark these are in alphabetical
对于水印 它们是按字母顺序排列的
order so it'll be down here at the
订购 这样它就会在下面的
bottom and the double use and click
底部和双重使用 然后单击
watermark and that will appear and we
水印 这将会出现 我们
can click on it up here as an option so
可以点击这里作为选项 所以
there's this drop-down when we it's
有一个下拉列表 当我们它
enabled right now if we click enable it
如果我们单击Enable It 立即启用
will show across here this marker is
将在这里显示此标记是
darktable
暗桌
we can change it to this has bulb which
我们可以把它换成这个有灯泡的
is a black square we can change it to
是一个黑色正方形 我们可以把它改成
this promo which shows information about
这一促销活动显示了关于
dark table and about the camera and lens
暗桌和关于相机和镜头的
this first one dark table also showed
第一张深色桌子也显示了
information about the camera and lens
有关相机和镜头的信息
and the metadata from the actual image
以及来自实际图像的元数据
has the dark table logo there and then
那里有黑色的桌子标志 然后
this last one is this simple text so we
最后一条是这个简单的文本 所以我们
can put in our own text and change the
可以放入我们自己的文本并更改
color and position of it so this is
它的颜色和位置所以这是
probably one we're going to want to do
可能是我们想做的一件事
right now you can play with the other
现在你可以和另一个一起玩了
ones but they're not incredibly
但他们并不令人难以置信
customizable this simple text is the
可自定义这个简单的文本是
only one that's built in that's
只有一个是内置的
customizable and then we can also add
可定制 然后我们还可以添加
our own so a fifth and a sixth and a
我们自己的 所以五分之一、六分之一和
seventh we can add our own custom ones
第七 我们可以添加我们自己的定制产品
in SVG format and I'll show you how to
SVG格式 我将向您演示如何
do that in just a second here but to
在这里只需一秒钟就能做到 但是
change this text we just click in text
更改此文本我们只需在文本中单击
and we can type in whatever we want
我们可以输入任何我们想要的东西
TJ photos and so we can have that there
TJ的照片 所以我们可以在那里看到
and then we can change the color of it
然后我们可以改变它的颜色
so we click here on color and maybe I'll
所以我们点击这里的颜色 也许我会
make this white and go select so now we
将此设置为白色 然后选择 因此现在我们
can have it really bold and on top there
可以让它变得非常大胆 在那里
if we want but we can make it more
如果我们想要 但我们可以做得更多
subtle by going to opacity and turning
通过变得不透明和转身变得微妙
down that opacity that's kind of the
在不透明的情况下 这是一种
transparency or how clear it looks zero
透明度或透明程度看起来为零
is all the way invisible and 100 is all
一直看不见 100就是全部
the way visible so maybe I'll put it
看得见的路 所以也许我会把它
down here to about like 17% or very very
下降到大约17%或者非常非常低
subtle
微妙的
there we have it we can change also the
我们有了它 我们还可以更改
scale the size of this we can scale it
规模大小我们可以扩大规模
down we can change the rotation so
向下 我们可以更改旋转 以便
people will rotate it and put it like
人们会旋转它 把它放在
this and then we can also change the
这样 我们还可以更改
position of it so right now it's a line
它的位置所以现在它是一条线
to the center we could align it to the
到中心我们可以把它对齐到
right we could line it to the bottom
好的 我们可以把它排到底部
right corner we could line to the bottom
在右角 我们可以排到底部
we'll just keep it Center aligned right
我们只要让它居中对齐就行了
now and then we can subtly do this X&Y
时不时地我们可以巧妙地做这个X&Y
offset to kind of subtly adjust where
偏移量可以微妙地调整到哪里
it's at within the picture so there we
它在照片里 所以我们在那里
go we have a nice sort of soft watermark
去吧 我们有一种很好的软水印
now across just with some simple text oh
现在只需要一些简单的文字哦
we can also change the font which is a
我们还可以将字体更改为
pretty important one so you might want
很重要的一个 所以你可能会想
to grab a font that's more any installed
获取安装了更多字体的字体
fonts you have on your system you can
您可以在系统中使用的字体
inst you can put over here alright so
你可以把它放在这里 好的 所以
that's the way to do basic text that's
这是做基本文本的方法 这是
using the built in module to add our own
使用内置模块添加我们自己的
in here it's a little bit more
在这里 它是更多一点
complicated first of all we need to
复杂 首先 我们需要
create it so if you already have a
创建它 以便在您已经拥有
watermark then we can just use yours you
水印 然后我们就可以用你的了
just need to put it in SVG format and if
只需将其转换为SVG格式 如果
we hover over just hover our mouse over
我们只需将鼠标悬停在上方
here the Mizzou min it'll tell us where
在这里 Mizzou Min它会告诉我们
to put these so it says SVG watermarks
把这些放在上面写着SVG水印
in your home directory so mine happens
在您的主目录中 这样我的就会发生
to be home TJ I'm using Linux so this
为了回家 TJ 我在用Linux 所以这个
file system might look a little
文件系统可能看起来有点
different than yours if you're using
与你的不同 如果你在使用
Windows and then send the dot config
Windows 然后发送.CONFIG
darktable in a folder called watermarks
名为水印的文件夹中的暗表
or it's also in the USR / share / share
或者它也在USR/Share/Share中
/ dark table / watermarks on Windows I
/Dark表/Windows i上的水印
believe it's either in Program Files or
我相信它要么在程序文件中 要么
maybe in your app data I'll try to
也许在你的应用程序数据中 我会尝试
include the link in the description this
将链接包括在此描述中
video of where to put it but what we
关于把它放在哪里的视频 但我们
need to do is go out of dark table and
我们要做的就是走出黑暗的桌子
find that directory so I'll minimize
找到那个目录 这样我将最小化
this and first of all I'll just show you
首先 我要向你们展示的是
you can use Inkscape I would recommend
你可以使用Inkscape 我推荐你
doing so I've done I've created a quick
我这样做了 我已经创建了一个快速
little logo here using Inkscape it's
这里的小徽标使用Inkscape它是
just a transparent background so
只是一个透明的背景 所以
anything we draw behind this Oh show you
我们在这背后画的任何东西 哦 给你看
real quick oh that I had to draw
真的很快 哦 我必须画画
something hoops anything we draw behind
有什么东西笼罩着我们身后的任何东西
here it'll show up so we can change the
它会在这里显示 这样我们就可以更改
color and it'll everything is Trant
颜色和它会一切都是Trant
everything in white is transparent in
所有白色的东西都是透明的
this that make sense and so I can't did
这很有道理 所以我不能这么做
a little bit of a gradient on black text
黑色文本上有一点渐变
don't know if I'll show up very well or
不知道我会不会表现得很好
not but anyway let's export
不是 但不管怎样 我们出口吧
this we want to save it actually as an
这是我们想要将其保存为
SVG so I'm gonna go to file and I'll go
所以我要去申请 我会去
to save and then I asked where do you
存钱 然后我问你在哪里
want to save it well we need to go to
想把它保存好 我们需要去
that location that dark table told us if
那张黑桌告诉我们的那个位置
we hover over this it's in the dot
我们在这上面徘徊 这是在点上
config dark table watermarks now on
配置深色表格水印现已启用
Linux a dot means it's a in a hidden
Linux一个圆点表示它是一个隐藏的
directory so we can find that if we do
目录 所以如果我们这样做了 我们可以找到
like this tells us all the everything in
就像这样告诉我们所有的一切
this directory well if we do LS - aah
如果我们做LS-aah 这个目录做得很好
there's a bunch of other files with a
还有一堆其他的文件
dot in front of them that dot means it's
他们前面的那个圆点表示它是
hidden so it's there we just can't see
隐藏在那里 我们就是看不见
it so this dot config is the one that we
所以这个点配置就是我们
want we can also see those files by just
我们也可以通过以下方式查看这些文件
right-clicking in here and going to show
在此处单击鼠标右键并显示
hidden files again all of these steps
再次隐藏文件所有这些步骤
are specific to most Linux operating
特定于大多数Linux操作系统
systems not Windows so if you're on
系统不是Windows 所以如果您在
Windows you can ignore all this part and
Windows您可以忽略所有这些部分 并
you'll have to find it to do it another
你必须找到它来做另一件事
way so now we have our dot config we'll
现在我们有了点配置 我们将
go into there we just need to find dark
走进那里 我们只需要找到黑暗
table so dark table is right here and we
桌子这么暗的桌子就在这里 我们
see there is no watermarks folder yet so
看 现在还没有水印文件夹 所以
we need to create that looks like we
我们需要创建一个看起来像我们
can't create it from within here so we
不能从这里创建它 所以我们
need to actually go here another way
实际上需要用另一种方式去这里
so let's what I've done now see I'm in
所以让我们看看我现在做了什么 看我加入了
the dialog for saving so I need to go to
保存对话框 所以我需要转到
my folders directory or to my file
我的文件夹目录或我的文件
explorer I need to go to home and then
探险家 我要回家 然后
find that and again same thing
一次又一次地找到同样的东西
right-click you can go to show hidden
右键单击即可显示隐藏
files if you're not seeing those and
文件 如果你没有看到这些文件
then we just need to go to darktable
然后我们只需要去暗桌
and first create the folder to save it
并首先创建文件夹以保存它
into au dot config I mean first dot
进入Au点配置我是说第一个点
config then darktable and we see the
配置 然后是暗表 我们看到
here some configuration stuff for
以下是的一些配置资料
darktable
暗桌
we've seen to right-click and go create
我们已经看到了右键单击并创建
directory and it will have to call it
目录 它将不得不将其调用
water marks spelled exactly like that
水印拼写完全一样
all lowercase hit enter now that this
现在所有小写字母都按Enter键
folders here and empty we can close out
这里的文件夹和空的我们可以关闭
of this and go back in and save our our
然后回去拯救我们的
SVG there so we go to save I know this
SVG在那里 所以我们去拯救我知道这个
seems a little complex but oh look it's
看起来有点复杂 但看起来很复杂
already there now so we're in that
现在已经在那里了 所以我们在那里
directory and we'll just call it we'll
目录 我们就称之为它 我们将
just call it up here TJ custom watermark
只需将其命名为TJ自定义水印
with some underscores for spaces and
使用一些下划线表示空格和
we'll hit save
我们将点击保存
so that's saved as an SVG file now we
所以现在我们将其另存为SVG文件
can we can see that SVG file if we were
如果是这样的话我们能看到那个SVG文件吗
to go into here config darktable
要进入此处的配置暗表
watermarks now we see that SVG file and
现在我们可以看到SVG文件和水印
also it's also seen by darktable now we
现在我们也可以在暗表上看到它
don't have to restart darktable we can
不需要重新启动暗表 我们可以
just come over here to our drop downs
就到我们这里来下拉吧
now and we have a new option
现在我们有了一个新的选择
mm-maybe just close the watermark and
嗯-也许只需关闭水印和
open it again
再打开一次
okay maybe go back to light table and go
好的 也许可以回到轻桌上 然后走
back into darkroom now it's there okay
回到暗室 现在它就在那里 好的
so we had to we had to reload dark just
所以我们不得不我们不得不重新装填黑暗
the darkroom not the program but just we
暗房不是节目而是我们
had to get you back in the darkroom and
不得不把你带回暗室然后
we show the drop down we can see now we
我们显示了现在可以看到的下拉列表
have another option
有另一种选择
TJ custom watermark that wasn't there
不存在的TJ自定义水印
before we click on that and that places
在我们点击那个和那个地方之前
the TJ custom watermark with all the
TJ自定义水印与所有
settings that was there before maybe we
可能我们之前就在那里的环境
just go to reset all the settings and do
只需去重置所有设置并执行
that drop down here we go so now we see
这下拉我们开始了 现在我们看到了
this watermark is placed over here
这个水印放在这里
doesn't look great on this photo we can
在这张照片上看起来不太好我们可以
align it maybe to the bottom left hand
可能会对齐左下角
corner and adjust that offset a little
拐角并稍微调整一下偏移量
bit so that it goes right to there and
比特 这样它就会直接到达那里
down to there adjust the scale a little
到那里 稍微调整一下刻度
bit so we'll put it there and then we
所以我们把它放在那里 然后我们
might want to do adjust the opacity and
可能需要调整不透明度和
I just kind of made this little
我只是做了这个小小的
watermark up quick so it doesn't that
快速打上水印 这样它就不会那样
black text I probably make that text
黑色文本可能是我写的文本
white or something but yeah that's how
白色什么的 但没错 就是这样
you do your own custom watermark and now
你可以自己定制水印 现在
that I've put it I line it to the bottom
我把它放在下面 把它排到底部
left and done this opacity like this let
向左 像这样做这个不透明的
me turn it up a little bit if we want to
如果我们想的话我把音量调大一点
apply it to every image in here what we
将它应用于这里的每一幅图像 我们
can do is just click on it in the light
我能做的就是在灯光下点击它
table area kind of how we've kind of
餐桌区域就像我们有一种
done this in the past just not with a
以前这样做过 只是不是用
watermark and we go to history stack and
水印 我们转到历史堆栈
click copy but then under the things to
单击复制 但在要复制的对象下
copy if we uncheck all the changes
如果取消选中所有更改 则复制
except for watermark and hit OK now it's
除了水印和点击OK 现在它是
just copied that watermark with the
刚把那个水印复制到
opacity and the location that we put it
不透明度和我们放置它的位置
now we can click on a couple of these
现在我们可以点击其中的几个选项
other ones and we can hold ctrl while we
其他的 我们可以在按住Ctrl键的同时
select all four of them and then we can
选择所有四个选项 然后我们就可以
go paste and then we can just paste that
去粘贴 然后我们就可以粘贴了
watermark on all four of these and now
所有这四个上面都有水印 现在
we see it yeah I did it we can't see cuz
我们看到了 是的 我做到了 我们看不见因为
it's off the screen we can see here
在屏幕之外 我们可以在这里看到
these things are
这些东西都是
Haller but they are going to be on there
Haller 但他们会在那里
if we double-click we can probably see
如果我们双击 我们可能会看到
that yeah it's down there so we need to
是的 它就在下面 所以我们需要
come in and adjust it just because of
进来调整一下 仅仅是因为
the size of these that we can see that
我们可以看到这些东西的大小
watermark so that is adding custom
添加水印 即添加自定义
watermarks to images in darktable and we
在暗表和我们的图像中添加水印
see that it added to all of those ones
看到它添加到所有这些
if we had a hundred pictures we could
如果我们有一百张照片
add a hundred at once this is a great
一次加一百个这是一个伟大的
way to watermark images if you're you
如果你是你
know gonna be sharing them with clients
我知道会和客户分享
or if you just want to put a tiny
或者你只想把一个小小的
watermark on with your your website or
水印与您的网站 或
something yeah if you have any questions
如果你有任何问题
or comments go ahead and leave them
或者评论继续 离开他们
below and I'll catch you in the next
下面 我会在下一个赶上你
video
视频